Let's take a look at the allocate command.
讓我們來看看 allocate 指令。
This is used to dynamically allocate VSAM, non-VSAM,
這用於動態配置 VSAM、非 VSAM，
and hierarchical file system HFS datasets.
以及分層檔案系統 HFS 的資料集。
So here we have an allocate command
這裡有一個 allocate 指令
with a whole bunch of operands telling it how to allocate.
搭配一堆操作數告訴它如何配置。
And we'll follow that up with the list DS command
接著我們會使用 list DS 指令
for the dataset that we just created.
查看我們剛剛建立的資料集。
And we can see that the record format
我們可以看到記錄格式
and the logical record length match
和邏輯記錄長度符合
along with some other information.
還有一些其他資訊。
It's important to note that the list DS command
請注意，list DS 指令
will return different information
會返回不同的資訊
for VSAM and non-VSAM datasets.
針對 VSAM 與非 VSAM 資料集。
You can also use the delete command
你也可以使用 delete 指令
to delete that dataset, like this.
來刪除該資料集，就像這樣。
And then if you enter the dslist test.data,
然後如果輸入 dslist test.data，
it will come back and say it's not in catalog.
它會回傳說該資料集不在目錄中。
That's a nice way of saying,
這麼說是委婉地表示，
I have no knowledge of that particular dataset,
我沒有關於該資料集的任何資訊，
so I can't give you any information about it.
所以無法提供相關資料。
Because the catalog is, it's just like a catalog.
因為目錄，就像一本目錄一樣。
It makes a list of frequently accessed datasets,
它會列出常用的資料集，
so if it's not in the catalog,
所以如果不在目錄裡，
we can't find it by name alone.
我們僅靠名稱是找不到的。
And if you're curious about the catalog,
如果你想了解目錄，
you can use the list cat command
可以使用 list cat 指令
to list all the entries in the catalog.
來列出目錄中所有的項目。
When you type list cat with no operands,
當你輸入 list cat 且不帶任何參數時，
you get a listing of all the catalog entries
會列出所有與你使用者 ID 有關的目錄項目，
associated with your specific user ID.
這些都是與你的特定用戶 ID 相關的條目。
As you can imagine, there are many other operands
如你所料，還有許多其他運算元
you can use with the list cat.
你可以用在 list cat 命令上。
And you can find them either by using the help commands
你可以用 help 指令找到它們，
or by looking them up in the manual.
或是在手冊中查閱。
Then there's list alc.
還有 list alc。
This shows you the currently allocated datasets.
它會顯示目前已配置的資料集。
When you run it with no operands,
執行時不帶運算元，
it shows you all the currently allocated dataset names.
會顯示所有目前配置的資料集名稱。
If you throw in status after list alc,
若在 list alc 後加上 status，
it'll show you the status of each dataset,
會顯示每個資料集的狀態，
which includes the termination disposition of the datasets.
其中包含資料集的終止處置方式。
It looks like we're trying to keep a lot of them here.
看起來我們想保留很多資料集。
And if you type list alc history,
如果你輸入 list alc history，
you get the creation date, expiration date,
你會看到建立日期、到期日期，
and the dataset protection for all those datasets.
以及所有這些資料集的保護設定。
That's a handy one.
這個指令非常方便。
It's important to realize the difference
了解 free 和 delete 的差別很重要，
between free and delete.
兩者之間的差異很重要。
And you'll see how that works here along with catalog.
接著你將看到它與目錄相關的運作方式。
So we'll start out with another allocate command,
我們將從另一個 allocate 指令開始，
which we've shortened to aloc here.
我們這裡將其簡稱為 aloc。
Then we list ds the dataset to see its information.
接著使用 list ds 查看資料集資訊。
Next, we follow that with a free command.
然後執行 free 指令。
And what this does is it deallocates the datasets
這會解除配置不再需要的資料集
or HFSs that are no longer needed.
或 HFS。
It basically says, I don't need this anymore.
基本上是告訴系統，我不再需要它。
It can be freed.
可以釋放它。
It also means that it can be used for output processing
這也表示它可以用於輸出處理
or routed to another user.
或傳送給其他使用者。
We can then go and delete it with the delete command.
接著可用 delete 指令刪除它。
And again, the list ds shows that it's not in the catalog.
list ds 再次顯示該資料集不在目錄中。
There are some restrictions and suggestions
對於資料集類型有一些限制和建議
about what types of datasets can, can't, should,
哪些可以、不能、應該
and shouldn't be deleted or freed.
和不應該刪除或釋放。
And I bet you know where to find that information.
相信你知道該去哪裡查這些資訊。
Okay, let's talk about the profile command.
好，我們來談談 profile 指令。
This command establishes, changes,
此指令用於建立、修改
or lists your user profile,
或列出你的用戶設定檔，
basically how you want to use your terminal.
基本上是你想如何使用終端機。
In this example, the message ID is on.
此範例中，訊息 ID 是開啟狀態。
There's some other information in there
裡面還有一些其他資訊
like the prefixing, prompting,
像是前綴設定、提示功能，
and primary and secondary languages.
以及主要與次要語言。
You can use the profile command
你可以使用 profile 指令
to not only display your profile settings,
不僅顯示你的個人設定，
but also to change them.
也可以修改這些設定。
These changes will remain valid
這些變更將在
for the duration of your session.
你的工作階段期間持續有效。
Lastly, the submit command.
最後，介紹 submit 指令。
This is how we send one or more jobs
這是我們提交一或多個作業的方法
to the system for processing.
送交系統處理。
Each job submitted must reside either in a sequential dataset,
每個提交的工作必須位於序列資料集內，
a direct access dataset,
或直接存取資料集，
or in a member of a partition dataset,
或分割資料集的成員中，
unless you use the asterisk function of a submit command.
除非您使用 submit 命令的星號功能。
That asterisk function tells the command
星號功能告訴指令，
that you will enter the data in some other way.
您將以其他方式輸入資料。
In the lab that follows this,
在接下來的實驗中，
we'll get to issue some TSO commands on a live system,
我們將對實際系統發出一些 TSO 命令，
which is almost certainly going to be more exciting
這幾乎可以肯定會更令人興奮
than watching me talk about them.
比聽我談論它們更好。